Finding Aid for the John Galsworthy Papers LSC.0417
UCLA Library Special Collections
John Galsworthy papers
1910-1933
UCLA Library Special Collections
Galsworthy, John, 1867-1933
LSC.0417
1.5 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
John Sinjohn Galsworthy (1867-1933) was born in Kingston Hill, Surrey, England. He studied law, but did not practice. He wrote plays and novels including The Silver Box (1906) and Man of Property (1906). The collection consists of correspondence between John Galsworthy and Dr. J. Morris Slemons, and also Galsworthy letters to various persons. Includes a typescript of The Freelands, newspaper clippings relating to Galsworthy and theater programs for Galsworthy plays.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. J. Morris Slemons, 1954.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9914704723606533
Biography
John Sinjohn Galsworthy was born August 14, 1867 in Kingston Hill, Surrey, England; studied law and called to the Bar in 1890, but did not practice; traveled extensively, meeting Joseph Conrad in the far east; his first play was The Silver Box (1906); his first successful novel, Man of Property (1906), began the first of a series collectively known as The Forsyte Saga; founded P.E.N. club; refused a knighthood, but accepted the Order of Merit in 1929 and the Nobel Prize in 1932; died January 31, 1933 in London.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence between John Galsworthy and Dr. J. Morris Slemons, and also Galsworthy letters to various persons. Includes a typescript with holograph corrections to The Freelands. Also includes newspaper clippings relating to Galsworthy and theater programs for Galsworthy plays.
Authors, English -- Archives.; Galsworthy, John, 1867-1933--Archives.
- Correspondence between Dr. J. Morris Slemons of Los Angeles, various bookdealers and other Galsworthy collectors. v.p., ca., 1929-1933.; 16 items. (Box 1)
- Ephemera by and about John Galsworthy., 7 items. (Box 1)
- Galsworthy, John, 1867-1933. Letters to various persons. v.p., v.d.; 15 items. Holograph and manuscript (Box 1)
  General note
  (Several letters are written by another person although signed by Galsworthy).
  - 1. Letter to Charles Harry St. John Hornby (b.1867), December 29, 1921.
- Newspaper clippings relating to Galsworthy, including obituaries., 1 folder. (Box 1)
- Galsworthy, John, 1867-1933. Preface to The Freelands. n.p., ca., 1915.; 5 leaves. Typescript(carbon) with holograph corrections. In a green morocco backed case. (Box 1)
- Theater programs for Galsworthy plays., 4 items. (Box 1)
- Looney, J. Thomas. Shakespeare Identified. London: Cecil Palmer, 1920.; 551pp. (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Presentation copy from John Galsworthy to C.H. St. John Hornby, Christmas 1921.
  Ex libris: C.K. Ogden.
- Original black dustjacket for Galsworthy's The Silver Spoon., 1 item. In a green morocco backed case. (Box 1)
- Serials (Box 2)